Dan Griffin

Sacramento, California Area

Regional Sales Manager at Broan-NuTone LLC

Summary

Experienced National Account Manager with a demonstrated history of working in the consumer goods industry. Skilled in Communication, Reading Comprehension, Ethics, Management, and Salesforce.com. Strong sales professional with a Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.) focused in Business Administration and Management, General from DePaul University - Charles H. Kellstadt Graduate School of Business.

Experience

Regional Sales Manager at Broan-NuTone LLC

June 2015 - Present (3 years 9 months)

Manage distributors and dealers in the Appliance Channel. Work with various rep agencies to grow sales and implement pricing/promotions. Train dealer sales people on our ventilation products. Secure display placement on dealer floors. Participate in multiple trade shows throughout the year. Exceeded sales plan in 2015 and 2016 (Best brand). Mentored 2 new employees for my previous roles/customers.

National Account Manager at Broan-NuTone LLC

June 2013 - June 2015 (2 years 1 month)

Managed major accounts in the Retail and Private Brands Channels. Participated in and won multiple line reviews generating incremental sales and shelf space for Broan products. Provided yearly forecasts. Opened a new customer account. Received Broan "Achievement Award" for exceeding sales plan.

Regional Sales Manager at Broan-NuTone LLC

April 2008 - June 2013 (5 years 3 months)

Managed major accounts in the Retail and Hardware Channels. Negotiated 25+ marketing/sales agreements. Delivered 14 price increases. Successfully completed 10 line reviews. Guided 4 rep groups to meet sales plans. Worked 6 customer buying markets per year.

Territory Sales Manager at Broan-NuTone LLC

March 2006 - March 2008 (2 years 1 month)

Managed 130+ accounts (Electrical/Plumbing/HVAC Distributors; K&B Showrooms). Conducted 50+ counter days/trainings with distributors. Completed 350+ contractor/builder sales calls.

Sales Associate at Broan-NuTone LLC

Education

DePaul University - Charles H. Kellstadt Graduate School of Business

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.), Business Administration and Management,

General, 2007 - 2011

University of Wisconsin-Madison

Bachelor of Business Administration (B.B.A.), Marketing, 2000 - 2004

Activities and Societies: Mu Kappa Tau Professional Honorary Marketing Society Hoofers Sailing Club

Dan Griffin

Sacramento, California Area Regional Sales Manager at Broan-NuTone LLC



Dan Atkinson

Greater Seattle Area

Regional Sales Manager at Miele

Summary

Senior-level professional with over 25 years' experience in managing clients, teams, projects, vendors and contracts while demonstrating a continuous focus on customer service, profitability and sales.

Experience

Regional Sales Manager at Miele

January 2012 - Present (7 years 2 months)

Senior level professional responsible for effectively managing Miele's Western region including Alaska, Washington, Oregon, Idaho, Wyoming, Montana and Northern California building, mentoring and leading a team of sales professionals. With over 25 years' experience in managing clients, teams, projects, vendors and contracts while demonstrating a continuous focus on customer service, profitability and sales. Coordinates communications, information and highly skilled professionals to creatively meet the needs of clients through well-managed projects, programming and sales initiatives. Strong interpersonal, written, verbal and listening skills that support the building of collaborative relationships and leading a highly effective sales team.

Territory Sales Manager at Luwa

December 2004 - January 2012 (7 years 2 months)

Managing independent appliance dealers in Washington, Idaho and Montana for a luxury appliance distributor and responsible for building strong alliances with local business owner's and their sales staff through customer service, relationship building and select distribution. Lead training and team building based projects to support improved sales and increased profitability for local business owners, recognized for superior customer service, sales and profitability for consistently demonstrating accountability and high level of customer focus.

Sales Manager at Lowe's Companies, Inc.

December 2000 - December 2004 (4 years 1 month)

Managed team of Specialists, ensured exceptional customer service, set sales goals and performed team building exercises. Led implementation projects for customer service and sales from small 2-person use tools to store content management solutions in use by all employees. Analyzed profit and loss statements and created programs that ensured maximum profitability in

all facets of the business. Responsible for all employee reviews, performance evaluations and Human Resources.

Retail Manager at The Home Depot December 1993 - December 2000 (7 years 1 month)

Recognized for taking a leadership role, team building, merchandising and sales initiative.

Received 6 promotions before being recruited by Lowes for a managerial position within their growing operation.

Education

University of Washington Civil Engineering, 1987 - 1988

Dan Atkinson

Greater Seattle Area

Regional Sales Manager at Miele



4 people have recommended Dan

"During my Miele tenure as one of Dan's Territory Managers in Northern California, I was awed by his ability to lead a team with such positive influence, fortitude, and perseverance. Dan's uniqueness as a leader is accomplished by a combination of a hands-on/hands-off approach. He allows his managers to work independently, creatively, and successfully; yet also knows when to mentor and guide. Dan's appliance industry knowledge is second to none in the Pacific Northwest and Northern California markets. His years in the business have given him an expertise that gives a distinctive advantage over his peers as well as his competitors. If you have a question, Dan will have the answer. This proof can be found in the success of his team in their sales as well as their professionalism in the field. I would recommend Dan Atkinson for any high level management position in the appliance world, but also in any industry for which he will lead a team."

—Stacey Vaughn, Associate Information Technology Consultant, bepress, reported to Dan at Miele

"I had the great fortune of working with Dan on a highly successful multi million project in Portland, the Cosmopolitan a high end mixed use development. Dan managed the entire appliance package with professionalism and strict adherence to our timelines. An asset to our industry!"

—Doug Shapiro AIA, LEED AP, Area Manager, MWH Constructors, was Dan's client

"Few people have the opportunity to report to a manager who is also a coach and mentor—but I did when I worked for Dan I had the pleasure of working for Dan for two years while at Miele, where our team significantly grew our region's business under his leadership. I was always in awe of Dan's ability to command a room and get people on board with ideas—even people who were initially on completely different pages. It amazed me how Dan could convince a room that two people with two completely different ideas were both right in their own way. It just was a matter of seeing it from each other's perspective. And no matter how tense meetings could get, Dan made sure everyone left with a confidence boost, energized and ready to accomplish whatever goals had been set. As a team member or a leader, Dan earns my highest recommendation."

-Kimberly Goldberg, Senior Account Executive, Georgia-Pacific LLC, reported to Dan at Miele

"I have the pleasure of working with Dan both in the capacity of one of his customers and on the executive team where Dan was our top performing sales representative. Dan is the kind of person that drives results. He's very adept at managing a sales team and getting the most from his teams talents as well as rolling up his sleeves and making it happen himself. As one of his customers Dan is bar none the most responsive contact we have an any of our suppliers. He always delivers on his promises and is quick to follow up with the actions that are happening behind the scenes to get something done. Any company that is looking for an experienced sales leader would do well adding him to their team."

—Mike Atkinson, VP of Operations / Supply Chain / Strategic Planning, Seattle Coffee Gear, was Dan's client

Erik Hendrickson

Charlotte, North Carolina Area

Director of Sales at Samsung Electronics America

Summary

I have worn multiple hats in my career thus far - everything from operations, strategy, sales, sales operations, merchandising retail channels and B2B within commercial industries. I have a unique ability to lead multi-dimensional projects and overcome challenges that are presented. I like to challenge myself to be a superhero both at work and at home - accomplishing the impossible at times.

Experience

Director of Sales at Samsung Electronics America January 2019 - Present (2 months)

Product Marketing Director - Home Appliances (Refrigeration) at Samsung Electronics America February 2017 - Present (2 years 1 month)

I lead a \$2 Billion+ HA category at Samsung

Full P&L Management

Strategic Cross Functional Engagement

Go-to-Market Strategizing

Customer Engagement & Growth

Talent Development & Management

Competitive Analytics

Product Lifecycle Management

Product Development

Supply Chain & Forecasting

Broker Associate at RE/MAX Suburban at RE/MAX Suburban

July 2015 - February 2017 (1 year 8 months)

Divisional Merchandise Director - Lawn & Garden at Sears Holdings Corporation October 2015 - December 2016 (1 year 3 months)

Vice President - Retail at Empire Today

March 2014 - April 2015 (1 year 2 months)

Charged with re-inventing the Empire Today brand by implementing retail showrooms as the company's key growth expansion plan.

- Developed and implemented a brick and mortar concept from inception including, but not limited to real estate site selection, showroom design, merchandise assortment, fixture prototyping, strategic planning and recruiting.
- Sales focused driven decisions along with strategic planning produced a sales experience better than anyone else in the industry.

General Manager - Appliance Builder Distributors at Sears Holdings Corporation July 2011 - March 2014 (2 years 9 months)

Full responsibility for Sales, P&L accountability, marketing, operations and human resources subsidiary luxury appliance businesses owned by Sears Holdings Corporation; consisting of 15 showrooms, 3 corporate offices and over 300 employees throughout Florida, Arizona, Nevada and Northern California. \$100M+ revenues.

- Through strategic changes and focusing on the operating excellences of the subsidiary group Transformed the business from being a profit drain to making over \$1M in EBITDA in less than a year.
- Made key strategic hires to focus the team on becoming a customer centric, sales driven organization driving significant top and bottom line revenue gains. Diversified the sales team to focus on the different channels within the portfolio.
- Drove incremental profit by negotiating strategic partnerships with key vendors allowing our sales team to provide best in class products and service.

Director Sales - Home Appliances at Sears Holdings Corporation October 2010 - August 2011 (11 months)

Strategic planning and leadership of all financial functions relating to the Home Appliance call center teams. These responsibilities included: running the sales team, managing a \$120M+ dollar revenue plan, coordinating multiple facilities, developing new initiatives while maintaining a focus on the bottom line EBITDA plan.

Operations Manager - Appliance Builder Distributors at Sears Holdings Corporation February 2010 - December 2010 (11 months)

ASSM - North Region at Sears Holdings Corporation August 2009 - March 2010 (8 months)

Appliance Select Territory Manager for the North Region.

National Manager - ABD Integration at Sears Holdings Corporation

2008 - August 2009 (1 year)

Product Manager - Sears Commercial at Sears Holdings Corporation

2006 - 2008 (2 years)

Branch Manager - Florida Builder Appliances at Sears Holdings Corporation

2005 - 2006 (1 year)

Florida Builder Appliances is a wholly owned subsidiary of SHC.

Operations ASM - Tampa FL at Sears Holdings Corporation

2005 - 2005

Brand Central ASM - Tampa FL at Sears Holdings Corporation

2003 - 2005 (2 years)

National Management Trainee at Sears Holdings Corporation

2002 - 2003 (1 year)

Education

University of Missouri Trulaske College of Business

BA, Business Management, 1998 - 2002

Activities and Societies: President - Phi Delta Theta Fraternity

University of Missouri-Columbia

Bachelor's Degree, Business, Management, Marketing, and Related Support Services, 1998 - 2002

Activities and Societies: President Phi Delta Theta

Erik Hendrickson

Charlotte, North Carolina Area

Director of Sales at Samsung Electronics America



3 people have recommended Erik

"I worked with and reported directly to Erik during his employment with Sears Holdings. Erik was responsible for supporting, leading and directing the Appliance Builder Distributor division. As the General Manager for ABD, Erik had demonstrated leadership management skills that were clear and supportive to our teams. Erik kept our subsidiaries on task while driving company results. His leadership style was consistent and accountable. Erik has earned my recommendation as a solid leader."

—Matt Hernandez, Director of Operations, HybridCore Homes, reported to Erik at Sears Holdings Corporation

"Erik is the consummate professional. I witnessed this when working with him on the Empire retail project. Erik's leadership skills shined throughout the project as he kept his team engaged and motivated all the while keeping his razor-sharp focus. It was inspiring to work with a leader who has impeccable work ethic and is compassionate about his team. He has my highest recommendation!"

—Bardha Zendeli, PMP, Senior Project Manager - Information Security, BMO Financial Group, worked indirectly for Erik at Empire Today

"I was pleased to promote Erik from his former position as Brand Central Manager to Showroom Store Manager in Tampa Florida. He did a great job of turning this operation around in short order. His leadership and selling skills paid off big time. While we did not work together for long, I have followed Eriks rapid advancement to the top of the Sears ABD Group and am not surprised at his success. HIs pleasant demeanor combined with the determination for success makes him a great business leader. Larry Lewis"

—Larry K. Lewis, Business and Government Consultant, Integrity Consultants LLC, managed Erik at Sears Holdings Corporation

Darrin Dillavou

Phoenix. Arizona Area

Regional Manager West- HA Builder Division at Samsung

Summary

Experienced builder of brands with a history of working in the consumer electronics and home appliance industries. Strong demonstrated background in taking existing brands into new channels as well as launching new brands against already entrenched competition.

Experience

Regional Sales Manager West- HA Builder Division at Samsung Electronics America April 2016 - Present (2 years 11 months)

Regional Account Manager AZ, NM, Las Vegas, and El Paso at Vent A Hood August 2012 - April 2016 (3 years 9 months)

Responsible for increasing market share in the Southwest for two industry leading brands in the Major Appliances; Vent A Hood and Lynx Professional Grills.

Territory Manager-AZ and NM at Almo Corporation July 2012 - August 2012 (2 months)

Sales Manager AZ, NM at Twin Eagles Premium Grills

April 2008 - June 2012 (4 years 3 months)

Growing brand awareness and sales by increasing floor displays and training. Conduct cooking demonstrations to grow partnership with BBQ community and sales teams while introducing the brand to the public.

District Manager at Noble Distributors Inc.

April 2005 - June 2012 (7 years 3 months)

Sales and leads development. Focus on training while working with manufacturer programs to assist my accounts profitably grow their business using our product lines.

Appliance Sales at The Great Indoors

August 2001 - March 2005 (3 years 8 months)

Retail appliance sales. Utilized product knowledge and lead development to drive business and lead location in sales for entire tenure.

Education

University of Phoenix

Darrin Dillavou

Phoenix, Arizona Area

Regional Manager West- HA Builder Division at Samsung

